<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FAQ on</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/</link><description>Recent content in FAQ on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 10:30:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Global Callback is Deprecated, How to Handle Global Scenarios?</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/global-callback/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:13:46 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/global-callback/</guid><description>It is planned to remove the global callback in the V9 version. If you are currently using the global callback function, you need to migrate to the new method as soon as possible. So, what method can be used to replace the global callback?
The answer is: Subscription Rules ( 👈 click to view usage instructions).
The menu entry for subscription rules is: Monitors - Rules - Subscription Rules TAB. Below is the interface for creating a subscription rule:</description></item><item><title>Should 'High CPU Load' Trigger an Alert?</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/cpu-alerting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:09:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/cpu-alerting/</guid><description>Should high CPU load trigger an alert?
If we don&amp;rsquo;t set an alert, we&amp;rsquo;re afraid of being blamed for missing alerts when problems occur. If we do set an alert, there seems to be too much noise, and engineers automatically ignore them. How awkward&amp;hellip;
The adult world is not black and white. To discuss this seriously, we need to add many qualifiers. To avoid ambiguity and align understanding, let me first introduce some prerequisite knowledge (principles).</description></item><item><title>Should upper-layer businesses receive alarms from underlying infrastructure?</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/biz-team-subscribe-infra-alarms/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:13:17 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/biz-team-subscribe-infra-alarms/</guid><description>A friend asked: I am a DEV or SRE of a business application. My application depends on underlying services and infrastructure, such as basic networks, Kubernetes, MySQL, and cash register services. Should I receive alarms if these basic services have problems? There is a subscription rule in Nightingale. Is it designed for this purpose?
This article presents the author&amp;rsquo;s personal understanding, for reference only.
First, please read the previous article &amp;ldquo;Should high CPU load trigger an alarm?</description></item><item><title>How to import Prometheus rules?</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/how-to-import-prometheus-rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:23:56 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/faq/how-to-import-prometheus-rules/</guid><description>Many people in the Prometheus ecosystem have shared alerting rules, such as this project:
https://github.com/samber/awesome-prometheus-alerts/tree/master/dist/rules Each directory contains alerting rules in YAML format. For example, the host-and-hardware directory includes common alerting rules for node-exporter. Want to directly import these rules into Nightingale? Please refer to the following steps.
Version # Please use Nightingale version 8.2.0 or later.
Import Steps # As shown in the screenshot above, go to the alerting rules page and select import to import Prometheus-format alerting rules.</description></item></channel></rss>