<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Practice on</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/</link><description>Recent content in Practice on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 19:41:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Linux OS</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:14:16 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/linux/</guid><description>For monitoring systems, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more critical. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, which will be categorized by different components. If you have good practice experiences with a certain component, you are welcome to submit a PR and attach your article link to the corresponding component directory.
Best Practices for Linux Host Monitoring Thoroughly Understand Machine Monitoring Through Node-Exporter FAQ # 1.</description></item><item><title>Process</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/proc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:15:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/proc/</guid><description>For monitoring systems, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more critical. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practices, categorized by different components. If you have good practical experience with a certain component, please submit a PR and attach your article link to the corresponding component directory.
Process monitoring consists of two parts: one is the statistics of the total number of processes in the operating system, and the other is the collection of metrics for individual processes.</description></item><item><title>Port</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/port/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:15:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/port/</guid><description>For monitoring systems, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more critical. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, which will be categorized by different components. If you have good practical experience with a certain component, please submit a PR and attach your article link to the corresponding component directory.
Port monitoring is a typical method for process liveness detection.</description></item><item><title>Plugin Scripts</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/exec/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:14:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/exec/</guid><description>For a monitoring system, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more critical. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, which will be categorized by different components. If you have good practical experience with a certain component, you are welcome to submit a PR and attach the link of your article to the corresponding component directory.</description></item><item><title>MySQL</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/mysql/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:14:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/mysql/</guid><description>For monitoring systems, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more critical. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, which will be categorized by different components. If you have good practical experience with a certain component, you are welcome to submit a PR and attach the link of your article to the corresponding component directory.</description></item><item><title>Redis</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/redis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:15:33 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/redis/</guid><description>For a monitoring system, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more important. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, categorized by different components. If you have good practical experience with a certain component, please submit a PR and attach the link to your article in the corresponding component directory.
Collect Redis Monitoring Data with Categraf Monitor MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, Oracle, Postgres, etc.</description></item><item><title>Oracle</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/oracle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:15:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/oracle/</guid><description>For monitoring systems, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more important. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, categorized by different components. If you have valuable practice experiences with a specific component, please submit a PR and attach a link to your article in the corresponding component directory.
There are various methods to collect Oracle monitoring data, such as using tools like Categraf and Cprobe.</description></item><item><title>Java Programs</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/java/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 20:14:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/practice/java/</guid><description>For monitoring systems, the strength of basic functions is indeed crucial, but how to implement them in different scenarios is even more critical. In the &amp;ldquo;Monitoring Practice&amp;rdquo; chapter, we collect various monitoring practice experiences, which will be categorized by different components. If you have good practical experience with a certain component, you are welcome to submit a PR and attach the link of your article to the corresponding component directory.</description></item></channel></rss>