<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pre-Introduction</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/pre-intro/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:42:33 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/pre-intro/</guid><description>Common installation methods include:
Binary deployment Docker Compose deployment Helm deployment The recommended method is binary deployment, for the following reasons:
Nightingale consists of a single binary file with minimal dependencies, making it easier to manage. Most users are familiar with systemd, so you can simply use systemd to manage the Nightingale process. Docker Compose deployment may have slightly lower performance compared to binary deployment, and it requires additional knowledge of Docker.</description></item><item><title>Upgrade</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:44:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/upgrade/</guid><description>Nightingale versions V6, V7, and V8 have the same upgrade method between their minor versions.
Upgrade Steps # Backup Data: Before upgrading, back up the MySQL database content, binary files, and the etc and integrations directories. Having a backup allows you to operate confidently. If you are using binary deployment, replace the binary files and the integrations directory (you can simply move the old integrations directory to a backup location using mv integrations integrations.</description></item><item><title>Binary Deployment</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/binary/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/binary/</guid><description>If you have not read the section on Pre-Installation Instructions, please do so before reading this section.
Download # Download the latest version from GitHub, and you will get a compressed package similar to n9e-${version}-linux-amd64.tar.gz. This is the release package for the X86 CPU architecture. If you need the ARM architecture, download the arm64 package. There is no Windows version of the release package because Nightingale is a server-side project that typically runs on Linux systems.</description></item><item><title>Docker Compose</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/compose/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/compose/</guid><description>Download # Refer to the Binary Installation section to download the Nightingale monitoring release package, which includes Docker Compose configuration files. Alternatively, you can directly download the Nightingale source repository, where you can also find the Docker Compose configuration files.
Start # Whether you download the release package or the source code repository, there will be a docker/compose-bridge directory after decompression. Simply enter this directory and execute the docker-compose up -d command (due to domestic network restrictions, image downloads may fail, and you need to solve the problem of scientific internet access on your own).</description></item><item><title>Helm</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/helm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 13:26:54 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/helm/</guid><description>You can run Nightingale using the n9e helm chart to deploy it in a Kubernetes cluster.
The default username for Nightingale is root, and the password is root.2020.
However, we do not recommend deploying Nightingale in Kubernetes because the monitoring system is too critical. If the Kubernetes cluster encounters issues, it may cause the monitoring system to malfunction. At that time, you might want to use the monitoring data to troubleshoot Kubernetes issues, leading to a circular dependency.</description></item><item><title>Configuration</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/configuration/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 14:14:47 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/install/configuration/</guid><description>The configuration file for the central n9e is etc/config.toml, and the configuration file for the edge alert engine n9e-edge is etc/edge/edge.toml. Here we first explain the n9e configuration file in sections.
Global # [Global] RunMode = &amp;quot;release&amp;quot; This is a configuration item used by Nightingale developers; ordinary users don&amp;rsquo;t need to care about it. It should always remain release.
Log # [Log] # stdout, stderr, file Output = &amp;quot;stdout&amp;quot; # log write dir Dir = &amp;quot;logs&amp;quot; # log level: DEBUG INFO WARNING ERROR Level = &amp;quot;DEBUG&amp;quot; # # rotate by time # KeepHours = 4 # # rotate by size # RotateNum = 3 # # unit: MB # RotateSize = 256 Output: Log output method, supporting stdout, stderr, file.</description></item></channel></rss>