<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:48:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/introduction/</guid><description>Nightingale is an open-source project focused on alerting. Similar to Grafana&amp;rsquo;s data source integration approach, Nightingale also integrates with various existing data sources. While Grafana focuses on visualization, Nightingale focuses on alerting.
Nightingale can query data from multiple data sources, generate alarm events, and then send alerts via various notification channels. In addition, we also have an event pipeline design, which can perform different processing on alarm events, such as filtering, relabeling, enriching, and so on.</description></item><item><title>Nightingale vs Prometheus</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/prometheus/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:12:27 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/prometheus/</guid><description>Nightingale is similar to Grafana in that it can integrate with a variety of data sources, the most common of which is Prometheus-type. Other data sources that are compatible with the Prometheus interface, such as VictoriaMetrics, Thanos, and M3DB, can also be considered Prometheus-type sources, so the relationship between the two is close.
If you have the following requirements, you might consider using Nightingale:
You have multiple time-series databases, such as Prometheus and VictoriaMetrics, and want to use a unified platform to manage various alert rules with permission control.</description></item><item><title>Prior knowledge</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/pre-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:24:26 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/pre-knowledge/</guid><description>Nightingale monitoring (Nightingale) is part of the Prometheus ecosystem, so many concepts and knowledge of Prometheus are prerequisites for using Nightingale. This article lists the key knowledge and provides relevant learning materials, hoping to be helpful to you.
Basic Knowledge # Linux knowledge, such as process-related, network-related, systemd-related, etc. Prometheus knowledge, which is essential for using Nightingale. You can refer to the Prometheus official documentation.</description></item><item><title>Architecture</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/architecture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:27:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/architecture/</guid><description>Nightingale&amp;rsquo;s architecture is relatively simple. For testing purposes, a single binary can be used to start it. However, for production environments, it relies on MySQL and Redis. Some companies have multiple data centers, and some edge data centers have poor network quality; Nightingale has been specifically designed to address such scenarios.
Architecture Diagram # If we do not consider the edge mode, Nightingale has only one main process, the n9e process, which relies on MySQL and Redis to store some management data.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Edition</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/flashcat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:35:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/flashcat/</guid><description>Nightingale&amp;rsquo;s core development team is fully dedicated to open source. Without a sustainable income, the project cannot continue. Therefore, they founded a company: Beijing Flashcat Cloud Technology Co., Ltd., abbreviated as &amp;ldquo;Flashcat&amp;rdquo; and launched two commercial products:
One-stop Intelligent Observation Platform Flashcat One-stop Alarm Response Platform Flashduty Among them, Flashcat can be regarded as the commercial version of Nightingale, positioned as a unified observation platform, while the open-source version focuses only on metric monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Videos for Getting Started</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 13:39:06 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/prologue/videos/</guid><description>To help users quickly get started with Nightingale, we have created a series of introductory video tutorials covering various aspects from installation and deployment to basic usage. Here is the list of these videos (it is recommended to watch at double speed for a quick overview):
Nightingale Project Introduction, Resource Links, etc., Must-Watch Nightingale Architecture Explanation Basic Functionality Introduction Installing Categraf for Nightingale Integration Introduction to Common Categraf Plugins Notification Rules Introduction</description></item></channel></rss>