<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quick Start on</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/</link><description>Recent content in Quick Start on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Sources</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/datasource/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:16:07 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/datasource/</guid><description>Nightingale supports integration with various data sources. Early supported data sources, such as Prometheus, VictoriaMetrics, ElasticSearch, etc., support both querying/visualization and alerting. As the project has evolved, Nightingale has positioned itself as an alert engine. Therefore, newly integrated data sources like ClickHouse, MySQL, Postgres, etc., only support alerting and not querying/visualization.
Whether you want to view data from a data source or set up alerts based on its data, you first need to configure the data source.</description></item><item><title>Ad-hoc Query</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/ad-hoc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 11:23:54 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/ad-hoc/</guid><description>Nightingale supports Ad-hoc queries, enabling direct querying of data from data sources through the interface. The menu entry is under Explorer; select Metrics to query metric data and Logs to query log data.
Metric Query # Here is an example of a metric query:
This page is similar to Prometheus&amp;rsquo; graph page, supporting queries for time-series metric data. Of course, some enhancements have been made, such as adding built-in metrics, history records, and other capabilities.</description></item><item><title>Metric Alerting</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/metric-alerting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:16:49 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/metric-alerting/</guid><description>Nightingale monitoring divides alerting into two parts: alerting and notification. Alerting refers to the periodic judgment through rules that ultimately generates alert events, while notification refers to the subsequent pipeline and notification process of alert events. This chapter first introduces the alerting part, and we consider it successful when an alert event is finally generated.
Alerting Principles # Nightingale supports two alerting modes: normal mode and advanced mode (the advanced mode is not open-source yet, but it is planned to be open-sourced later):</description></item><item><title>Log Alerting</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/logs-alerting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:16:19 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/logs-alerting/</guid><description>Nightingale monitoring supports log alerting, which allows configuring alert rules for log data in data sources such as ElasticSearch, Loki, and ClickHouse. It periodically queries the data sources and triggers alerts when the data in the data sources meets the alert thresholds. The main difference between log alerting and metric alerting lies in the writing of query conditions. Other fields are common, so please be sure to read the content of Metric Alerting first, which will not be repeated here.</description></item><item><title>Notification Rules</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/notify-rules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:16:57 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/notify-rules/</guid><description>Alarm rules are responsible for generating alarm events, and notification rules are responsible for sending out alarms. Different alarms can use different notification media. For example, high-level alarms can be sent via phone calls, SMS, or DingTalk, while low-level alarms can be sent via email.
Design Purpose # Older versions of Nightingale did not have the concept of notification rules. Notification media and recipients were directly configured in alarm rules. Although this was intuitive, it lacked flexibility, with the following issues:</description></item><item><title>Dashboard</title><link>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/dashboard/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 17:15:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://n9e.github.io/docs/usage/dashboard/</guid><description>Although Nightingale monitoring focuses on alerting, it also supports dashboard functionality. While it may not be as sophisticated as Grafana, it supports common chart types and can meet daily usage needs.
Quick Import # We have previously organized machine dashboards that you can directly import to quickly see the effects. The import method:
Different collectors collect monitoring metrics with different names and labels, so separate dashboards need to be created for each.</description></item></channel></rss>